So, for this last part,
最后这部分课程
we're going to go from this into this dashboard here.
我们将从这里完成这个仪表板
So, how do we go from here to here exactly?
如何从这里到这里呢?
Well, the main difference is that I have made multiple charts here,
主要区别在于我在这里绘制了多个图表
so these are all just div ID-0,
所以这些就是 div ids[0]、
div ID-1, div ID-2, div ID3,
div ids[1]、div ids[2]、div ids[3]
and I'm just placing them into the Bootstrap front-end that you made earlier.
我只是将它们放入了之前制作的 Bootstrap 前端
So it might seem a little intimidating,
看起来有点吓人
but it's actually just putting everything together that you've already been practicing.
但实际上只是将已经练习过的所有内容放在一起
Okay. So, here is
这里是
my final code and I'm going to walk you through it so that you can see what I did.
我的最终代码 我将带你逐步了解 看看我都做了什么
Index.html has all of the front end code with Bootstrap.
index.html 拥有 Bootstrap 的所有前端代码
So this might be vaguely familiar
所以这可能会觉得有点熟悉
because we already went through this and you practiced using Bootstrap.
因为我们已经学过这些内容 并且你使用 Bootstrap 进行了练习
So this is importing all of
这里是导入
the Bootstrap files here and I'm also importing the scripts for Plotly,
所有的 Bootstrap 文件 也为 Plotly 导入了脚本
the plotly library and then going down here,
plotly 库 然后滚动到下方
this is just all of the Bootstrap front end that you were
这就是你之前写过的所有 Bootstrap 前端
working with before like this is the navigation bar up here,
比如这里的导航栏
all of this code is the navigation bar,
所有这些代码都是导航栏
and then here is just dividing everything up into rows and columns.
然后这里就是将所有内容划分为行和列
So there's the Linkedin logo,
有 Linkedin 的 Logo
there's the Git Hub logo scrolling down here is where the plots actually start.
有 GitHub 的 Logo 滚动向下 这里就是图表开始的地方
So nothing new here.
这里没什么新东西
This is the h2 tag,
这是 h2 标签
this is the h4 tag, keep going down.
这是 h4 标签 继续向下
Okay. So this is really the only thing that's
这个确实是我们从未在 Bootstrap 中看过的唯一新事物
I'm just putting in here a Div with an ID of
我只是在这里放置了一个 id 为第一幅图表的 div
the first chart and then here I'm putting a Div with the ID of the second chart,
然后在这里 我放置了 id 为第二幅图表的 div
a Div with an ID of the third chart,
id 为第三幅图表的 div
and here a Div with an ID of the fourth chart,
以及这里 id 为第四幅图表的 div
and then scrolling down,
然后向下滚动
this just has the same JavaScript code from before where we're
这只是我们之前写过的 JavaScript 代码
just iterating through these variables that came
遍历这些变量
from the backend to put everything on the front end.
把所有东西从后端传到前端
So the only thing that's really new here it's just adding these divs with the IDs of
所以这里唯一的新东西就是添加了这些 div
the visualizations in them that's all I've changed from
和其中的可视化 id
when we were working on the front end earlier in the lesson.
这就是与本课程前面所作的前端工作的所有不同之处
It gives me this which is pretty cool, right?
这样的改动带来这些结果 很酷吧?
So, the next thing to talk about is actually
所以 接下来要讨论的就是
these visualizations themselves and how I wrote the code on the backend.
这些可视化本身 以及我如何在后端编写代码
Let's go back to routes.py.
我们回到 routes.py
So, I refactored a lot of the code to make routes.py a lot simpler.
我重构了很多代码 使 routes.py 变得更加简单
So, all I'm doing here is actually in this return figures method
我所做的都在这个 return_figures 方法中
which comes from this wrangling-scripts.wrangle-data file over here,
该方法来自 wrangling_scripts.wrangle_data 文件
I am actually just doing all of
我实际上做的就是回到那个文件
the data wrangling and getting all of the Plotly figures ready back there,
将所有数据整理好 以及将所有的 plotly 图表准备好
so that it doesn't even show up in the routes.py file.
所以这些都没有出现在 routes.py 文件中
This code is exactly the same as before.
这段代码与以前完全相同
It just iterates through this figures list and makes the IDs,
只是遍历这个 figures 列表并创建 ids 变量
and then converts figures into Jason and then passes the variables to the front end.
然后将 figures 转换为 JSON 然后将变量传递给前端
So, the perhaps scary part that did take me a long time
让我花了很长时间的可能令人恐惧的部分
is the data wrangling and for better or for worse,
是数据整理 无论好坏
a data scientist usually has to do a lot of data wrangling.
数据科学家通常不得不做很多数据整理
So what did I do? I wrote a function that cleans
那么我都做了什么呢? 我写了一个函数
the CSV files in a generic way because all
以通用的方式清理 CSV 文件
of the CSV files have the same format and they come from the World Bank.
因为所有 CSV 文件具有相同的格式 都来自世界银行
So I wrote this function here that just cleans everything up.
所以我写了这个函数 清理好所有数据
Again, I'm going to give you this code and you can look through it,
同样 我将为你提供这些代码 你可以仔细阅读
it's going to be an example that comes after the exercise that I'm going to give you.
可以作为后续练习的示例
Now we have this return figures function and all it does is set up
现在到了 return_figures 函数 它的功能就是
the code for all four of
为全部四个可视化设置代码
the visualizations and there's a lot of code but if you look at it little by little,
其中有很多代码 但如果你一点一点地看
I think it's relatively interpretable and it's similar
我认为这是比较好懂的
to what I was showing in the last part of this screencast.
类似于上一部分录屏视频中演示的内容
So here we have graph 1 and this is where all of the graph 1 information is going to go.
这里我们有 graph_one 存储所有 graph_one 的信息
So first I clean the data,
首先清洗数据
I'm just changing the column names,
我修改了列名
I'm doing a little bit of sorting so that everything shows up in
做了一些排序 使所有东西在可视化中按需求有序显示
is what I showed very similar to what I did
然后这部分展示的与我之前所做的非常相似
before where I'm iterating through each country
迭代每个国家
and then I'm appending the information to the graph 1 visualization.
然后将信息追加到 graph_one 可视化中
So this is all of the code.
这就是所有的代码
Here's the layout just for this visualization here on the left.
下面是布局 只是针对左侧的这个可视化
Then for chart 2,
然后对于图 2
I again am cleaning the data and then this time I only wanted data from 2015,
再次清理数据 这次我只想要 2015 年的数据
so the wrangling was a little bit different.
所以数据整理稍有不同
I wanted to make a bar chart,
我想绘制一个条形图
so here I put on the x-axis the countries and
所以在这里我在 x 轴上放置了 country
then on the y-axis I put the values and I'm using Pandas and Python to do all of this.
然后在 y 轴上放置了对应的值 我使用了 Pandas 和 Python 来完成这些操作
Here's the layout for number two,
这是第二个布局
and again, this is the bar chart here in the upper right.
再次对照 这是右上角的条形图
Moving down, we've got the code for chart 3 where again,
向下移动 我们得到了图表 3 的代码
I'm iterating through and building this up country by
遍历国家来创建这些内容
country and putting multiple lines on one visualization.
在这个可视化中放置多条折线
Then I have the layout and then comes the fourth chart which is this one in the bottom
然后是布局 接着是第四个图表 也就是右下角这个
right and I am just cleaning the data again,
再次清理数据
I have to merge the two datasets together that's what's happening in 128 and
我得将两个数据集合并在一起 也就是第 128 行代码的操作
then iterating through the countries and setting up the visualizations.
然后遍历各个国家并设置可视化
This one had a little bit more wrangling to do because I had multiple CSV files.
这个图表的数据整理会多一点 因为涉及多个 CSV 文件
Another thing I should point out is that actually if you look here in each graph,
还需要注意一件事 你可以在每个图表的代码中看到
I have name equals country.
都有写 name = country
So I have this country variable and it was
这个 country 变量
really important that I left the countries in the same order,
一定要使各个国家按照相同的顺序排列
so that they kept showing up with the same colors over here.
这样它们就会一直使用相同的颜色
So, I was using the same list of countries in the same order every time so
我每次都使用相同顺序的国家列表
the Plotly would automatically use the same colors in all of my visualizations.
所以 Plotly 会在所有可视化中自动使用相同的颜色
Then, keep scrolling down.
继续向下滚动
Okay, so once I have all of this ready,
好的 准备好这一切之后
I'm appending each visualization to this figures lists and then returning figures.
我将每个可视化追加到这个 figures 列表 然后返回
So going back to roots which is actually using this return figures function,
回到 routes 文件 也就是实际调用 return_figures 函数的地方
it just returns all of the figures and it's ready to go.
该函数返回了所有图表 准备好了
So that's how I did it. It did take me a good amount of time to do all the wrangling to
这就是我做的工作 确实花了很多时间来做整理并重构代码
refactor the code and again it's part of being a data scientist.
这就是数据科学家工作的一部分
The thing is is that for
提醒一下
this exercise at the very end
课程最后的练习
of this lesson where you're going to make your own data dashboard,
制作自己的数据仪表板
you can reuse a lot of my code.
你可以复用我的很多代码
All you're really going to have to do is change maybe
你真正需要做的就是修改
index.html to put in links to your own GitHub repo or
index.html 链接到自己的 GitHub 存储库或
your own GitHub account into your own Linkedin account and
自己的 GitHub 帐户、自己的 Linkedin 帐户
then you might want to add or take away visualizations and in that case,
然后你可能想要添加或删除可视化 这样的话
you're going to want to scroll down and make sure you have
你需要向下浏览 确保
enough Divs for each visualization that you're going to make.
为绘制的每个可视化提供足够的 div
Roots wrangling is where the bulk of your work is going to go.
你需要完成的大部分工作都在 wrangling 文件中
You're going to have to figure out how to clean your data and get it in
你得弄清楚如何清理数据使其成为正确的格式
the right format so that it works in Plotly, and that's it.
确保其可用于 Plotly 就是这样啦!